CONTACT

juanpcarrascal@gmail.com

jpcarrascal

ipcarrascal

JUAN PABLO CARRASCAL

UX Researcher | UX Research Manager

I am a mixed-methods UX researcher and manager with experience in discovery and evaluative research in multiple domains. I have conducted research on developer tools, web and cloud, mobile, music applications, and non-standard form factor interfaces. I help product teams to learn from and to empathize with their users, in order to design digital products and services that solve real problems.

EXPERIENCE

Principal UX Research Manager

Microsoft - Developer Division (Barcelona)

2023 - Current

I lead a team of researchers working on Azure (Microsoft's cloud) developer tools and services. I team up with product managers, designers and engineers to plan and conduct mixed-method discovery and delivery research, communicate results to stakeholders, and promote a learningdriven, user-centric culture.

Senior UX Research Manager

2021 - 2023

Microsoft - Developer Division (Barcelona)

UX Researcher / Senior UX Researcher

2018 - 2021

Microsoft - Developer Division (Barcelona)

UX Researcher II Microsoft - Developer Division (Redmond, WA) 2017 - 2018

Postdoctoral Fellow

2015 - 2016

Human Media Lab - Queen's University (Canada)

I designed, developed and evaluated Organic User Interfaces and related interaction techniques. My work was conducive to several publications in top-tier HCI conferences

Sound Director / Musician / Engineer

2008 - 2009

Tiempo de Cine (Bogotá, Colombia)

2006 - 2007

Lecturer in Sound for Communication

Universidad Javeriana (Cali, Colombia)

Freelance Musician / Producer / Sound Designer **Various**

2003 - 2010

EDUCATION

Ph.D. - Information and Communication Technologies (summa cum laude)

2015

Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Barcelona)

Thesis title: Aspects of Information Valuation in Web Browsing and Mobile Communication. Internships at Yahoo! Labs (Sunnyvale, CA, 2014) and Telefónica Research (Barcelona, Spain, 2011-2014).

LANGUAGES

English

Full professional proficiency

Spanish

Native

M.Sc. - Information and Communication Technologies

Universitat Pompeu Fabra (Barcelona)

Thesis title: Multitouch Interface for Audio Mixing...

B.Sc. - Electronic Engineering

Universidad del Valle (Colombia)

2003

2023

2010

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Full list: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=sCs_VWAAAAAJ

Juan Pablo Carrascal and Ina Ghita. Intangible: A reflection on digital vs. physical co-ownership. In *Proceedings of the Seventeenth International Conference on Tangible, Embedded, and Embodied Interaction*

2022

Juan Pablo Carrascal. Count-me-in: A collaborative step sequencer for audience participation. In *Proceedings of the 19th Sound and Music Computing Conference, SMC2022*

2020

Kelly Krout, Juan Pablo Carrascal, and Travis Lowder-milk. Lean ux research at scale: A case study. In *Proceedings of the Conference on Mensch Und Computer*

2019

Juan Pablo Carrascal, Kelly Krout, Jacob Freiberg, and Irina Smoke. Gamifying ux research at scale. In Extended Abstracts of the Annual Symposium on Computer-Human Interaction in Play Companion Extended Abstracts

2013

Juan Pablo Carrascal, Christopher Riederer, Vijay Erramilli, Mauro Cherubini, and Rodrigo de Oliveira. Your browsing behavior for a big mac: Economics of personal information online. In *Proceedings of the 22Nd International Conference on World Wide Web*

PATENTS

Monty Hammontree, Travis Lowdermilk, Valentina Strachan, Maxim Lobanov, Kelley Zhao, Steven Clarke, Jessica Rich, and Juan P Carrascal-Ruiz. Machine learning query session enhancement. US Patent 11,615,144

2021

Monty Hammontree, Valentina Strachan, Travis Lowdermilk, Maxim Lobanov, Kelley Zhao, Steven Clarke, Jessica Rich, and Juan P Carrascal-Ruiz. Query and information meter for query session. US Patent 11,055,329 2021

Rodrigo de Oliveira and Juan Pablo Carrascal. Method for collecting and storing annotations associated to a voice audio data. US Patent 8,792,863

2014